<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Codebase]]></title>
  <link href="http://jam1401.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jam1401.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-18T10:32:08-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jam1401.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jeff Morgan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Playing with Google Wear I]]></title>
    <link href="http://jam1401.github.io/blog/2014/07/18/playing-with-google-wear-i/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-18T09:16:14-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jam1401.github.io/blog/2014/07/18/playing-with-google-wear-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Android Wear Core Experience</h1>

<p>The Android Wear UI consists of two main spaces centered around the core functions of <strong>Suggest</strong> and <strong>Demand</strong></p>

<h2>The Context Stream (Suggest)</h2>

<p>This is effectively Google Now for Android Wear whereby users can swipe through a list of contextually relevant cards. Cards in the stream are more than simple notifications they can be swiped horizontally swiping may reveal buttons which allow actions</p>

<p><img src="http://developer.android.com/wear/images/screens/stream.gif"></p>

<h2>The Cue Card (Demand)</h2>

<p>The cue card allows users to speak to Google. Swiping up on the cue card shows a list of suggested voice commands which can also be tapped.</p>

<p>Each suggested voice command activates a specific type of intent. Multiple applications may register for a single voice intent and the user will have the opportunity to choose which application they prefer (yuk .. seems like an area for some contextual help)</p>

<p>Applications can respond to a voice command in the same way as they respond to a tap on a regular in-stream action button. by adding or updating a stream card or by launching a full screen application.</p>

<p><img src="http://developer.android.com/wear/images/screens/cuecard.gif"></p>

<h2>Other Features</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Home Screen</strong> is the default state and has a background, status indicators and the top ranked context card can be seen poking up from the bottom of the screen</li>
<li><strong>Ambient Mode</strong> some devices may put the device into ambient mode, users can exist ambient mode by tapping on the screen.</li>
<li><strong>Settings Screen</strong> is a cue card and fairly self describing</li>
<li><strong>Full Screen Apps</strong> can be launched on top of the man screen where a wider range of interaction is called for.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/design/downloads/index.html#Wear">Useful Downloads</a></p>

<p>There will be more later</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lets Start this up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jam1401.github.io/blog/2014/02/15/lets-start-this-up/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T12:56:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jam1401.github.io/blog/2014/02/15/lets-start-this-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well lets try this again. I remember starting an octopress blog well over a year ago. A lot has changed since then. Back then I was at working for <a href="http://www.snapfish.com">Snapfish</a> building out a new IOS application and service, seconded to <a href="http://pivotallabs.com">Pivotal Labs</a> to learn XP and basis for running good agile products. Now I work for <a href="http://www.sisa.samsung.com">Samsung Research America</a>, working mostly in Android and Rails with a smattering of other stuff.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Quite a journey but perhaps one where I have learned as much as I possibly could about state of the art software systems development and deployment.</p>

<p>WIth this blog (which I will try to keep updated) I will hopefully discuss some useful and interesting things related to my craft</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
